NORMAN LO

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/norman-data-economist/ Phone: (415) 706-8788 Address: San Francisco, CA 94107

GitHub: https://github.com/NormanLo4319

Website: https://normanlo4319.github.io/Norman Lo Web/ E-mail: lokman@mail.sfsu.edu

SUMMARY

Data scientist with several years of experience in academic research and data analysis. Experienced in data management and statistical packages, such as Python, R, Stata, MatLab, E-View, VBA, SQL, and Javascript. Currently enrolled in Berkeley Data Analytic boot camp for keeping up with the recent technology and best practices. Motivated to bring background in academic research and ability to build econometrics models with visualization to enhance decision-making and achieve company goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Javascript, Python, R, Stata, E-View, MatLab, SQL, noSQL, VBA

Data Manipulation & Visualization: pandas, matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau, Plotly, D3, ggplot2, scikits

Database: mySQL, postgeSQL, mongoDB, SQLAlchemy Other: Git, Flask, command line, machine learning, bit data

PROJECTS

World Happiness Project

- Built a backend API with SQLAlchemy and Flask App for data request.
- Created frontend data product to request data from the API and provided visualizations for clients.
- Demonstrated the correlation between happiness and income inequality across 156 countries.

Public Health Scores & Yelp Customer-Based Rating

- Analyzed the restaurants' public health score and Yelp customer-based rating in San Francisco.
- Pulled and stored data from Yelp API and SFDPH on over 2000 restaurants into SQL database.

Food Environment & Health Outcomes

- Requested data from Yelp API and CDC public health data for over 200 counties in the U.S.
- Generated statistical analysis and visualizations created using Python, Pandas, and Matplotlib.

EXPERIENCE

Student Equity Economics Advisor, City College of San Francisco	(2017 – present)
Adjunct Faculty, DVC, SFSU, USF, CCSF, Metro. State University	(2015 – present)
Native English ESL Teacher, South Korea	(2010 - 2013)
Merchandising Manager, First Global International Ltd, Hong Kong	(2007 - 2010)
Senior Merchandiser, Hallmark Cards Corp, Hong Kong	(2005 - 2007)

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: U.C. Berkeley Extension, San Francisco

A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programing skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

M.A. in Economics: San Francisco State University, San Francisco **B.A. in Economics:** San Francisco State University, San Francisco